<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>4 | BuildENVIRONMENT!</title>
    <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication_types/4/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://nheeren.github.io/publication_types/4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>4</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Niko Heeren 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 23:34:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://nheeren.github.io/images/icon_huc789a8a7510c924dc77e79ade1e0c129_549_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication_types/4/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Efficiency and Climate Change: Material Efficiency Strategies for a Low-Carbon Future</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/irp-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 23:34:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/irp-2019/</guid>
      <description>













  


&lt;video autoplay loop &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;RECC%20Social%20media%20video.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Full report and more details follow soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report was developed by the IRP in response to a request by  leaders of the Group of 7 nations in the context of efforts to promote  resource efficiency as a core element of sustainable development. It  conducts a rigorous assessment of the contribution of material  efficiency to GHG abatement strategies. More concretely, it assesses the reduction potential of GHG emissions from material efficiency  strategies applied in residential buildings and light duty vehicles, and reviews policies that address these strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the Panel, GHG emissions from the material cycle of  residential buildings in the G7 and China could be reduced by at least  80% in 2050 through more intensive use of homes, design with less  materials, improved recycling of construction materials, and other  strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Significant reductions of GHG emissions could also be achieved in  the production, use and disposal of cars. IRP modelling shows that  GHG emissions from the material cycle of passenger cars in 2050 could  be reduced by up to 70% in G7 countries and 60% in China and India  through ride-sharing, car-sharing, and a shift towards trip-appropriate  smaller cars, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increasing material efficiency is a key opportunity to achieve the  aspirations of the Paris Agreement. Materials are vital to modern  society, but their production is an important source of greenhouse  gases. Emissions from material production are now comparable to those  from agriculture, forestry, and land use change combined, yet they have  received much less attention from the climate policy community. As shown by IRP estimates, it is time to look beyond energy efficiency to reduce global carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nullius in verba -- A guideline proposal for data accessibility and transparency in industrial ecology research</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/hertwich-dttf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/hertwich-dttf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konzept Energieversorgung 2050</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/jakob-2014-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/jakob-2014-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2000-Watt-Gesellschafts-taugliches Energiekonzept für die Stadt Zürich</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/jakob-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/jakob-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gebäudeparkmodell Vorstudie zur Erreichbarkeit der 2000-Watt-Ziele für Wohn-, Büro- und Schulgebäude in der Stadt Zürich Anhang zum Schlussbericht: Graue Energie und Umweltbelastungspunkte</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/heeren-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/heeren-2000/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gebäudeparkmodell Zürich – 7-Meilenschritte – Wirkungsanalyse anhand des Gebäudeparkmodells Stadt Zürich</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2010-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2010-b/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gebäudeparkmodell Zürich – Büro-, Schul- und Wohngebäude – Vorstudie zur Erreichbarkeit der Ziele der 2000-Watt-Gesellschaft für den Gebäudepark der Stadt Zürich</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2010-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2010-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gebäudeparkmodell Schweiz – SIA Effizienzpfad Energie, Dienstleistungs- und Wohngebäude</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/wallbaum-2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lebensdauerkosten von Oberbautypen mit verschiednen Schwellenmaterialien unter Einbezug ökologischer Aspekte</title>
      <link>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/weidmann-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nheeren.github.io/publication/weidmann-2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
